

MARTEL CARPIO ANDY

MASTER IN APPLIED INFORMATICS

CONTACT

- Prospekt 60-Letiya Oktyabrya, 11, Moscow, 117312
- **+**7 977-773-8978

FOLLOW ME

- andymartel.com
- @andyymartel
- github.com/aymartel
- w vk.com/aymartel

LANGUAGE

SPANISH



RUSSIAN



ENGLISH



I'm an enthusiastic detail-oriented Master in Applied Informatics who graduated from The National University of Science and Technology of Russia (MISIS) I am also Software Engineer from the University of Computer Science of Cuba (UCI).

I have 3 years of experience in web development working with REACT and Angular technologies using Javascript, HTML, CSS languages. I also have experience as a graphic designer working with Adobe Creative Suite specifically Illustrator and Photoshop. I'm very proactive and I'm always trying to learn new skills.



EDUCATION

> UCI - HAVANA

SEPT 2011 - JUNE 2016

Bachelor of Computer Science.

>MISIS - MOSCOW

SEPT 2019 - JUNE 2022

Master's Degree in Informatics Applied to Design.



EXPERIENCE

> UCI - CUBA

JULY 2016 - SEPT 2016

My first professional work was after graduated from the university. This was a small project part of a video-vigilance solution developed in Visual Studio and c#. My responsibility in this project was the front end development of the client application using Windows Form.

> CITMA - CUBA

SEPT 2016 - JULY 2017

I started at the Ministry of Science, Technology, and Environment of the Republic of Cuba (CITMA) developing institutional websites. The websites of the ministry were developed in WordPress with a small team of 3 people. I made some graphic designs for the webs using Illustrator and Photoshop and added to the web page created with wordpress new functionalities using HTML, Javascript and CSS

> CITMA - CUBA

SEPT 2017 - JULY 2018

I started giving support to a human resources software suite. This was developed with MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, NodeJS.

My responsibilities there were solving small issues and giving data support to the users.

SKILLS

Javascript CSS HTML

Data base Containers

O.O.P. Git C.V.

SKILLS

Teamwork Creative

Problem Solving Detailed

Time Management

TOOLS

- ♠ Git
- Visual Studio Code
- Ps Photoshop
- Ai Illustrator

HOBBIES

Sports Movies Music

Tv Series Travels

EXPERIENCE

> CITMA - CUBA

JULY 2018 - AUGUST 2019

I was assigned to a team of 5 people to develop an internal web solution for managers that shows statistical results. The software shows gadgets in a dashboard with updated information of science results, environmental issues, and other information.

I was involved in the front end layer, using ReactJS, Redux, HTML5, Bootstrap, Sass and GIT. This was a very interesting project that made me focus on web frontend technologies.

> BIT2ME - RUSSIA

SEPT 2019 - JULY 2020

I worked as customer support agent in the area of cryptocurrencies. My responsibilities were respond in spanish to users via designated support interface and via phone calls. Search for incoming transactions, Carrying out stuck transactions. Stay updated with the company's product, its features and functionality and how our users experience it to provide professional support to users.

> FRELANCER GRAPHIC DESIGNER SEPT 2020 - JULY 2022

During my Master's studies I worked as a freelancer graphic designer working with the Adobe suite, I carried out Branding projects creating the corporate identity of small businesses for which I also designed graphic elements (logos, banners, business cards, brochures, billboards, posters, etc.)

> FRELANCER WEB DEVELOPMENT SEPT 2019 - JULY 2022

I worked on several freelancer web development projects. Using the MERN knowledge stack (MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js.) although more focused on the front end and using NextJs I developed landing pages for companies in the medical sector, commerce and the art of NFT. I also worked on Search Engine Optimization (SEO) projects designing and developing strategies for better internet positioning.

